JAY SYLVESTER

PRODUCT DESIGN ENGINEERING MANAGEMENT

https://jaysylvester.com

https://linkedin.com/in/jaysylvester

jay@jaysylvester.com

(484) 868-2184

Experienced **design and engineering manager** and **first design hire** at multiple SaaS startups. Adept at taking products and features from **concept to launch / 0 to 1**. Team-builder and mentor with **8 years of management experience.**

CORE SKILLS

Team Management / Mentorship
User Experience / Product Design
Discovery / Research / Competitive Analysis
Product Strategy / Design Thinking
Full-Stack Engineering

PROFESSIONAL ATTRIBUTES

Thoughtfully balances Product, Design, and Engineering concerns Inspires, manages, and mentors designers and engineers Intuits elegant and insightful solutions to complex problems
Thinks simultaneously at a systems- and product-level
Defines and implements just enough process to get things done

WORK HISTORY

Product Designer

Rockerbox - April 2022 to December 2023

- · As the company's first design hire, established a user-centered discovery and design process
- · Led user research and usability testing, presenting findings to the entire organization during quarterly presentations
- Spearheaded a product strategy based on distilling complex marketing data into key insights and intelligent recommendations through the use of automated analysis, plain language, and clear visualizations

Principal UX Designer

Equinix - July 2021 to April 2022

- · Led design efforts for the Equinix Metal co-location admin interface
- · Proposed and designed several major features to enable easier bare metal resource deployment and maintenance
- Created design concepts for the first iteration of a complete admin redesign and modernization effort

UX Manager

Linode - February 2019 to November 2020

- Managed the UX team responsible for the Cloud Manager admin UI
- Implemented the company's first moderated usability studies and presented findings to leadership regularly
- Completely redesigned the Cloud Manager based on user research and competitive analysis, making it easier for customers to deploy and manage a single virtual machine or a fleet of hundreds

UX Lead

Vidyo - October 2015 to January 2018

- · Joined the company as an individual contributor and promoted to UX Lead in my first year
- Player-coach to the UX team responsible for research and design across an entire suite of video conferencing products
- Built a fully functional prototype of a completely redesigned desktop app using Electron

WORK HISTORY CONTINUED

Creative Director

Fitly - February 2014 to July 2014

- · Led the responsive redesign of a startup incubator e-commerce product under an extremely tight deadline
- Implemented a rapid mobile-first design process consisting of mobile wireframes, front-end code, and on-the-fly design in the browser for tablet and desktop experiences
- · Followed up quickly with design comps for the second phase, refining the visual design and enhancing usability

UX Lead

Hibu - October 2012 to June 2013

- Managed a blended UI team consisting of UX designers and front-end developers
- · Led the responsive design project for the core e-commerce product, making a desktop-only site mobile-friendly
- Rearchitected and completely rebuilt the front-end code base for improved performance and maintainability

Manager of Front-End Development

Abercrombie & Fitch - April 2010 to May 2012

- · Managed a large team of UI engineers responsible for all e-commerce front-end development
- Built strong partnerships with stakeholders, UX architects, visual designers, and my IT colleagues, breaking down traditional silos and getting all teams working collaboratively
- · Overhauled the front-end code base, drastically improving site performance and maintainability

Senior Front-End Developer

Weblinc - May 2009 to April 2010

Lead Developer

NetPlus Marketing - April 2006 to August 2008

Web Specialist

Ricoh Corporation - October 2004 to May 2006

Web Producer

Panasonic - May 2000 to October 2004

SKILLS INVENTORY

JIRA · Agile · Sketch · Figma · Frontend Development · Backend Development · HTML · JavaScript · CSS · Node.js
PostgreSQL · SQL · Git · Linux · Terminal · Slack · Cloud Computing · Developer Tools · UX · Product Design
User Research · Personas · Archetypes · Usability Studies · User Testing · Heuristic Evaluation · Accessibility
Design Thinking · Requirements Gathering · Wireframes · Prototypes · High-Fidelity Mockups · Data Visualization

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, English - Pennsylvania State University